yamaha-motor.co.id 2019-04-23

# Privacy Policy - Privacy Policy | Yamaha Motor Co., Ltd.

Our commitment to safeguarding your personal information

## Yamaha Motor Group - Privacy Policy

Yamaha Motor Group declares that we properly manage personal information obtained through our business activities in accordance with principles below and proactively utilize the information to improve our services.

1\. Establishment of the Personal Information Protection Structure
    We will have individuals who work for each Yamaha Motor Group company recognize the importance of protection of personal information and will also establish the personal information protection structure. In addition, by clearly stipulating management rules for obtaining, use, and provision, etc., of personal information, we will properly manage personal information and make efforts for continuous improvement. 
2\. Proper obtaining
    We will obtain personal information within the scope of proper business activities to the extent necessary for achieving clear purpose of use by lawful and fair means and, if necessary, with the notification to the individual or public announcement of the purposes of use. 
3\. Restriction of use
    Unless otherwise agreed by the individual or permitted by laws and regulations, personal information shall not be used for any purpose other than those notified to the individual or publicly announced.
4\. Accuracy of the data, etc.
    When retaining personal information, we will keep it to meet the purposes of use as well as to keep it accurate, complete and up-to-date. When it is no longer necessary, we will endeavor to delete it without delay. 
5\. Security control
    When retaining and managing personal information, we will take appropriate security measures to prevent such risks as loss, destruction, falsification, and leakage. 
6\. Confidentiality duty
    Individuals who work for each Yamaha Motor Group company will recognize the importance of protecting personal information and make every effort to keep personal information confidential. 
7\. Response to inquiries, etc.
    When retaining personal information, we will publicly announce the purpose of use and our inquiry contact, and will respond faithfully to the request for disclosure, correction, and cessation of use, etc. 
8\. Actions in case of an accident
    If any accident such as leakage of personal information occurs, we will appropriately respond to it by investigating all facts and the cause and taking measures to prevent secondary damage and reoccurrence, etc. 
9\. Compliance
    In addition to the above matters, each Yamaha Motor Group company shall comply with laws and regulations related to privacy protection. 
10\. Utilization of personal information
    While complying with the above matters, we will proactively utilize obtained personal information to improve our services. 

(Revised on May 25, 2018) 

For the privacy policy of each Yamaha Motor Group company, see the following website and select company in your region:   
<https://global.yamaha-motor.com/link/>

## Handling of Personal Information

Based on the Japanese Act on the Protection of Personal Information, Yamaha Motor Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as “YMC”) publicly discloses the following items on the handling of personal information at our company.

1\. Use within the purpose of use
    We will use obtained personal information within the scope of the purpose of use to execute our business activities. 

2\. Provision of personal information to a third party
    We do not provide obtained personal information to any third party without the consent of the individual. However, we could provide personal information to a contractor in order to outsource services relating to handling of personal data. Even in this case, we will require the contractor to properly handle the personal information we provided as well as we will appropriately manage the information. 
3\. Appropriate management of personal information
    We will take appropriate security measures to prevent such risks as unauthorized access to and loss, destruction, falsification, and leakage of personal information. In addition, we will focus on activities to raise awareness of employees, etc., who handle personal information including giving periodic training/education for protection of personal information. 
4\. Joint use
    Each YMC Group company could jointly use obtained personal information. 

  * For more detail of Handling of personal information of customers
  * For more detail of Handling of personal information of shareholders/investors

## Disclosure of the Purpose of Use of Personal Information 

## Correction, Cessation of Use, Deletion, and Cessation of Provision to a Third Party of Personal Information

We will respond to a request for correction, cessation of use, deletion, and cessation of provision to a third party of retained personal information. If you have such a request, please make the request through the following procedure:

https://global.yamaha-motor.com/policy/disclose/

(Revised on May 30, 2017) 

## Handling of Personal Information of Customers

1\. Retained personal data
    We will retain the following personal data of customers: 

  * Personal information of customers who registered their Yamaha Motor products (motorcycles, motor scooters, electrically power assisted bicycles, marine products including boats, yachts, Marine Jet and outboards, and pools, etc.);
  * Personal information of customers who applied for any of various license schools;
  * Personal information of customers who asked for repair of our products;
  * Personal information of customers who registered with membership services;
  * Personal information of customers who requested for materials including product brochures;
  * Personal information of customers who contacted our inquiry desk;
  * Personal information of customers who answered to any questionnaire survey;
  * Personal information of customers who participated in any event/campaign;
  * Personal information of customers who participated in any facility tour;
  * Personal information of persons who concerned any accident relating to our products.

2\. Use within the purpose of use
    We will use obtained personal information of customers for the following purposes: 

  * (1) Giving commercial information relating to merchandise/services we provide;
  * (2) Planning, development, quality enhancement and improvement of merchandise or consideration on measures to improve customer satisfaction, etc., and questionnaire survey in order to achieve them;
  * (3) Performing works necessary to respond to inquiries, requests, etc. from customers and provide prompt services, etc.;
  * (4) Other purposes of use clearly specified at the time of obtaining personal information;
  * (5) Response based on any notification, instruction, requirement, or investigation request, etc., from any agency of national or local governments, the Japan Automobile Manufacturers Association, the Japan Marine Industry Association, or other public institutions.  
In addition, when we give information to customers through distributors of YMC and Yamaha Motorcycle Sales Japan Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as “Distributors”), we provide personal information to Distributors.

3\. Provision of personal information to Third Parties
    Except for the cases stipulated in paragraphs 2.(5) above, we do not provide obtained personal information to Third Parties without the consent of the customer. However, we could provide personal information to a contractor in order to outsource services relating to handling of personal data. Even in this case, we will require the contractor to properly handle the personal information we provided as well as we will appropriately manage the information. 
4\. Joint use
    Each YMC Group company could jointly use personal information of customers. 
     Purpose of use | Same as Paragraph 2 above  
---|---  
Personal information items | Address, name, contact (phone number, email address, etc.), product information, and details of consultation from the customer  
YMC Group | Yamaha Motor Co., Ltd., Yamaha Motorcycle Sales Japan Co., Ltd., Y'SGEAR CO., LTD., Yamaha Motor Powered Products Co., Ltd., and others  
Person responsible for management of joint use | Yamaha Motor Co., Ltd.  
  
5\. Inquiry desk
    Please contact the following desk for any inquiry and consultation on personal information of customers: 

  * “Inquiry Desk for Personal Information, Customer Communication Center”
  * TEL: 0120-090-819 (toll-free)
  * Reception Time : 9:00-12:00 / 13:00-17:00 Monday to Friday (except for holidays and day off prescribed by YMC, etc.)

     For any request including disclosure of the purpose of use of personal information of customers, see the following website:   
https://global.yamaha-motor.com/policy/disclose/
    We will obtain personal information to the necessary extent by lawful and fair means after clearly indicating the purpose of use. When you contact our Customer Communication Center, we will record the conversation to check the content. In addition, please note that we have introduced caller ID display function in order to call you back.

(Revised on May 30, 2017)

## Handling of Personal Information of Shareholders/Investors

1\. Retained personal data
    We will retain the following personal data on shareholders/investors: 

  * Personal information of shareholders described in the shareholders’ list;
  * Personal information of investors who registered with membership services.

2\. Use within the purpose of use
    We will use obtained personal information for the following purposes: 

  * (1) To exercise the rights or perform the obligations in accordance with the Companies Act;
  * (2) To provide benefits for the position of shareholder from YMC; 
  * (3) To take various measures to smooth the relationship between shareholders and YMC; 
  * (4) To manage shareholders including creating a data of shareholders according to the prescribed standard based on various laws and regulations;
  * (5) To deliver IR-relating information to investors by email. 

3\. Provision of personal information to a third party
    We do not provide obtained personal information to any third party without the consent of the shareholder/investor. However, we could provide personal information to a contractor in order to outsource services relating to handling of personal data. Even in this case, we will require the contractor to properly handle the personal information we provided as well as we will appropriately manage the information. 
4\. Inquiry desk
    Please contact the following desk for any inquiry and consultation on personal information of shareholders/investors: 

  * “Investor & Shareholder Relations Group, Corporate Communication Division”
  * TEL：0538-37-0134
  * FAX：0538-47-4250
  * Reception Time : 9:00-12:30 / 13:30-17:00 Monday to Friday (except for holidays and day off prescribed by YMC, etc.)

     For any request including disclosure of the purpose of use of personal information of shareholders/investors, see the following website:   
https://global.yamaha-motor.com/policy/disclose/

(Revised on May 30, 2017)
